当时我就在那里 面对赛伦盖提
So there I was, face to face with the biggest,
…最大最凶猛的花豹，然后…
meanest leopard on this side of the Serengeti. And...
你大吼一声 吓得他的豹纹掉满地
You roared so loud, his spots flew clean off.
爸，这故事我听过N遍了
Dad, I've heard this like a billion times.
你听我说过 有一次我把奸笑土狼
Do you know the one where I made the laughing hyenas...
…弄哭，对吧？  听过了
Cry? Yep.
我被鳄鱼攻击？  爸
The croc attack?  Dad.
好啦，我再想想看
OK. Think.
好吧，尽管想吧
Yeah, you do that.
我想到了，聪明小子
All right, Mr. Smart Guy,
你一定没听过这个故事
here's one I know you haven't heard.
故事发生在一个小地方 我称它
It all started in the little place I like to call...
…大草原
...the wild.
【野蛮任务】
他们是大草原 跑得最快的牛羚
They were the fastest wildebeests on the savannah.
他们真的超快的
We're talking fast.
其他的狮子早在 几小时前就放弃猎捕他们
All the other lions had given up the hunt hours ago,
除了你老爸
except your old man.
还好我知道一条捷径
Fortunately, I knew a short cut.
我自以为困住他们了 但尘沙散去
I thought I had 'em. Until the dust cleared.
才发现中了牛羚的圈套
Classic wildebeest trap.
你怎么办？
So, what did you do next?
我怎么办？  对啊
What did I do?  Yeah.
我大吼一声
That's when I gave them the roar.
就这样？  好戏在后头
That's it?  Hold on a sec.
我以为这样就搞定了
I only thought it was over.
不过他们有一项秘密武器
But they had a secret weapon.
我从没见过那么大的牛羚
He was the biggest wildebeest I've ever seen.
足足有四公尺高  才四公尺？
He was 14 feet tall!  Fourteen?
我是说四百公尺 又三十公分
I meant 1,401 feet tall!
酷毙了
Cool.
而且他还有两只…不，四只
And he had two... No, four
最巨大的牛羚角
of the biggest horns I'd ever seen.
哇塞  他喷出红色的气焰
Whoa!  His breath was red hot!
我是说绿色的啦
I mean, green.
而且他超讨厌这鬼地方
And he hated the environment.
我知道要打败他 一定要激发我内心深处
To pull this off, I knew I was gonna have to dig deep,
前所未有的勇气
deeper than I ever had before.
于是我强忍住恐惧
So I swallowed my fear,
深深地吸了一口气
sucked in the biggest breath I could.
爸，我准备好了
Dad, I'm ready!
你行吗？  我行！
You got it?  I got it!
我行！  那就让他好看吧
I got it!  Well, let him have it!
大声吼吧，儿子
Roar, son!
（纽约市立动物园）
每次都是这样
Story of my life.
你的吼声吓跑一群牛羚 我的吼声只会逗小朋友笑
Your roar stops a herd of wildebeests. Mine makes the babies laugh.
别气馁，你这次好多了
Hey, come on. That was much better.
我是说真的 降了半个八度
I'm serious! It dropped half an octave.
你再降半个八度 我都会被你吓到皮皮挫
It dropped half an octave. And it sure scared me.
让我全身的毛都竖起来  才怪咧，爸
Made my hair stand up on end.  Yeah, right, Dad.
好吧，再练一次  今天就练到这里
OK. Let's take it from the top.  I'm done for today.
别这样嘛，再来一次 就差这么一点点
Come on, come on, one more. You were so close.
也许是技术性问题
Maybe it's something technical.
也许你的嘴巴张得不够大 要像这样子
Maybe you're not opening your mouth wide enough. Like this.
爸，多谢你的技术指导
Dad, thanks for the technical help,
不过你要我吼得跟你一样 就得带我到真正的大草原
but if you wanted me to roar like you, you'd take me to the wild.
你有没有搞错？ 咱们在这里应有尽有
Hold on a second. We've got everything we could ever want here.
生活很享受 每天照三顿吃饭
Great lifestyle, three squares a day.
超无聊的  无聊？
It's boring.  Boring?
我在这里学不会狮吼  雷恩
I'll never learn how to roar here.  Ryan.
不过你放心 我终于想出办法
But don't worry. I finally figured out
怎么去野外  真的吗？
how we can get to the wild.  You did?
鸽子说那些绿色箱子 都是运到那里
The pigeons say those green boxes go there.
那些箱子不吉利 离它们远一点
Those boxes are bad news. Stay away.
可是，爸…  我知道你很郁卒
But, Dad...  I know you're frustrated,
不过狮子在这里 也能学会大吼
but a lion finds his roar...  Here.
爸，你老是说这种话哄我
I'm so tired of hearing that, Dad!
有一只老鼠
It's a rat!
快把那只老鼠赶走
Get that rat off my baby!
老鼠？
A rat?
你好
Hello!
好好玩的老鼠哦
Silly, silly rat.
老鼠才不喜欢这种手环，小姐 你这小…
Rats do not got bling like this, lady.  You little...!
那是我见过最丑的小贝比
Lastly, that is the ugliest baby I've ever seen!
斑尼，你偷小贝比的糖果？
Benny, stealing candy from a baby?
别说得这么难听 我只是怕他会蛀牙
Stealing is such a strong word. I prefer "liberating."
小鬼，我听到你的吼声 又降了…
Hey, kid, heard the roar. Down another...
八度  八度！
Octave.  Octave!
你要来替我跟你爸加油 看我们连续第五次夺下
You ready to cheer me and your old man as we capture our fifth straight
冰龟赛冠军吗？
turtle-curling title?
我根本就不会吼叫 你怎么知道我在加油？
I can't even roar. How would you even know I'm there?
你真的觉得降了八度吗？
So, you really think it dropped an octave?
当然罗
Absolutely.
八度到底是什么东东？  我听见了
What the heck is an octave?  I heard that.
兔子  胆固醇太高，我吃坚果
Rabbit.  Cholesterol. I'll stick with the nuts.
我不知道他的问题出在哪儿
I don't know what his problem is, Benny.
他都已经11岁了 可是吼声还停在9岁的程度
He's 11, but he's still roaring at a nine-year-old level.
山大王，帮个忙
Little help here, Sammy?
你知道吗？ 也许你的标准太高了
You know what? Maybe you're setting the bar too high,
你老是提那些山大王 在大草原的英勇故事
with all those stories about Samson the Wild.
他超爱听那些故事的 对他是一种激励耶
Hey, he's always loved those stories! They inspire him.
好啦，我不想跟你吵 我怕你拿我的尾巴当牙线
OK. I'm not gonna argue with someone who can use my tail as dental floss.
你的牙缝有渣渣  哪里？
You got something right there.  Where?
不对，另一边  这边？
No, no, other side.  Here?
抱歉，斑尼  弄出来了
Sorry, Benny.  You got it.
亲爱的大朋友小朋友
Attention, friends.
别忘了到礼品店购买 全国最抢手的填充玩偶
Stop by the gift shop and get the most popular plush in America:
尼啾无尾熊 会说「我喜欢你」
Nigel, the "l-Like-You" Koala.
瞧，亲爱的，它会说话耶  我是小可爱，我爱你
Look, honey! The crazy thing talks!  I'm so cuddly! I like you!
没错，他超可爱的 更赞的是，他喜欢你
That's right. He's so cuddly. And better yet, he likes you.
终于…
Finally.
动物园就快是咱们的天下了 倒数三秒
And the zoo will officially be ours in T-minus three...
（纽约市立动物园）
...two...
两秒
...and showtime!
好戏上场！
我来也
Here I come!
谁把栅栏放在这儿？
Who put that bar there?
好痒哦
That tickles!
我有啦  才没有
Did too!  Did not!
我有  才没有
给我让开，懒惰鬼
Out of my way, ya bum!
那个讨厌的无尾熊在哪里
There's that moth-eaten koala!
我跟你们这些火鹤说过一百遍 给我滚开
I've told you flamingos a hundred times, walk.
我要签名  不行
How about an autograph?!  Don't...
各位鸟兄弟 帮我找他背后的拉线
Birds! Find the string on his back!
你今天的心情很好耶  各位
So you're havin' a really nice day!  Guys.
别碰我的副队长
Off my co-captain, now.
抱歉，山大王
Sorry, Samson.
一点都不痛
That didn't hurt.
我差点忘了告诉你 我终于要约BJ出去
I almost forgot to tell you. I'm gonna ask Bridget out finally.
等一下，罗密欧 你是只松鼠，她可是…
Slow down, Romeo. You are a squirrel and she is...
跟我很速配，对吧？
Perfect, right?
我懂你的意思啦 相信我，我的眼睛是雪亮的
Look, I know what you're sayin'. Believe me, I got my eyes wide open.
走路不长眼啊，你这大…
Watch where you're goin', you big...!
别盯着我的斑点看，斑尼 我的眼睛在上面
BJ Bridget.
Don't stare at my spots, Benny. My eyes are up here.
当然了，歹势哦 这是送你的，小亲亲
Of course. I'm so sorry. Oh, this is for you, honey.
可以戴在左脚上面
It goes around your left hoof.
你从垃圾堆捡来的吗？
Did you get that out of the trash?
就是了，你这捡垃圾的脏鬼
You did! You trash-picker!
我不是捡垃圾 我是在做资源回收
I'm not a trash-picker. I'm a recycler.
这样比较浪漫，不是吗？
That's a lot more romantic. Isn't it?
浪漫？  山大王，过来
Romantic?  Sam, come here.
浪漫？ 别跟我谈浪漫，斑尼
Romantic? Don't mention romance to me, Benny.
我从来没有交过男朋友  那正好
I've never had a boyfriend.  That settles it.
我自愿当你的第一位男友
I accept the job... of boyfriend number one.
斑尼，只有雌性圆网蜘蛛
Benny, only the female orb-weaver spider
才会和比她小二十倍的 男生约会
will date a male one-twentieth her size.
我还是有希望  然后她会吃了他
So there's hope!  And then she eats him.
至少他死得很快乐
But at least he dies happy.
兄弟，我们去找雷恩
Let's get Ryan, dude!
兄弟，我们真有默契耶
Dude! We said that at the same time!
兄弟
Dude.
喂，雷恩
Hey! Hey, Ryan.
我要去参加比赛了 待会见，好吗？
Listen, I'm headin' down to the game. I'm gonna see you there, right?
来嘛，雷恩，我们需要你 你是我们的头号粉丝
Come on, Ryan. We need you. You're our biggest fan.
山大王 我才是你的头号粉丝
Yo, Samson! I'm your number one fan, man!
谢了，老兄 我也是你的粉丝
Thanks, man. Right back at ya!
爸，你刚才要说什么？
You were saying, Dad?
听着，今天下午我只是想…
Listen. About this afternoon, I was just trying...
爸，没事啦 我会去看你比赛，好吗？
Dad, fine. I'll go to your game, all right?
好吧，那就…待会见罗
OK. I'll... see you there, then.
来吧，兄弟
Come on, dude.
兄弟  你猜谁来了？
Dude.  Guess who's here?
伊斯、杜克
Eze. Duke.
讨厌，他每次都猜对
Man, he always guesses.
大家都去看比赛 我们可以趁机追捕瞪羚
We're gonna stalk the gazelles while everybody's at the game.
你来不来？  来嘛，小兄弟
You in?  Let's go, bro!
雷恩小兵
The Ryanator.
我这就下来
I'm comin' down.
鱼头！ 冷冻鱼头特价大拍卖！
Fish heads! Get your ice-cold fish heads!
免费赠送鱼眼哦
Now eyeball-free!
冰龟锦标赛进入最后一局
We're into the final period of the curling championships
轮到企鹅队上场 维特要丢了
and the penguins are up. Here comes Victor.
好样的
What a beauty!
好耶，快刷呀
Yeah, sweep!
直接朝着红心滑过去 这次很可能直接命中目标
Heading straight for the bull's-eye! This could be it, folks!
命中目标  好耶！
Bo-wango!  Yes!
好耶  这下很难打败他们了
Oh, yeah!  That's gonna be tough to beat.
什么？「很难打败他们」？
What? "Tough to beat"?
这才是我们最爱的挑战 对吧，大伙儿？
That's just the way we like it, right, guys?
我不敢相信
I can't believe this!
如果输了，我就要拧断 我的脑袋，还有你的
If we lose, I'm gonna rip my head off! And yours!
咱们可不能输给那群 不会飞的笨鸟
We cannot lose to flightless birds!
拜托，咱们不会输了这场比赛
Whoa, whoa. No one is losing anything around here.
只要大家保持专注
As long as we stay focused.
对了，有人看到雷恩吗？  我知道了
By the way, has anyone seen Ryan?  Oh! I know!
也许他活在老爸阴影下 心情很郁卒
Maybe he's sulking 'cause he lives in his father's shadow
而且他的吼声和女生一样逊
and he roars like a schoolgirl.
多谢了，赖瑞  不客气
Thanks, Lar.  You betcha!
尼啾，在我的玩偶上面签名
Nigel! Nigel! Will you sign my dolly?
不要吧  尼啾，别理他们
Not again.  Nigel, ignore them.
我是小可爱，我爱你
I'm so cuddly! I like you!
你超可爱的，我们都爱你  够了，我一点都不可爱
You're so cuddly! We love you!  That's it! I am not cuddly!
我是来自伦敦街头 在道上混的丛林狠角色
I'm a vicious jungle animal from the streets of London!
怕了吧  抓住他！抓住他！
Fear me!  Get him! Get him! Get him!
救命啊！  美眉们，把他放下来
Help me!  Girls! Put him down.
我不是玩偶
I am not a doll!
软绵绵的小屁屁  别摸我的屁股
Cushy tushy!  Leave my bum alone!
尼啾，别碰我的女朋友
Nigel! Get your paws off my girlfriend!
斑尼，我又不是你的女朋友
Benny, I am not your girlfriend!
好棒的一天哦
Really nice day!
山大王队是怎么了？ 逊毙了
What is up with Samson's team tonight? Brutal!
斑尼？
Benny?
天啊，谁会口对口人工呼吸？
Oh, my gosh! Who knows mouth-to-mouth?
我会
I do!
这算什么？
What was that?
你每天所需的斑尼维他命 宝贝儿
Just your daily dose of vitamin Benny, baby.
给我滚开  我是小可爱，我爱你
Get off my nose.  I'm so cuddly, I like you!
给我闭嘴  你好，老兄
Stop saying that!  G'day, mate!
我要跳罗
Cannonball!
明年我只要当教练
Next year, I should just coach.
你看，汤氏瞪羚
Check it. The Thomson gazelle.
4点5秒内就能加速到 时速80公里
Zero to 50 in four-point-five seconds.
速度最快的逃命高手  无人可比
The ultimate fleeing machine.  There is no substitute.
咱们靠近一点看看这群瘦子
Let's get a closer look at these slim jims.
这样好吗？  当然好
Shall we?  I think we shall.
也许应该去看比赛
Maybe we should just go to the game.
你不是想当野蛮动物吗？  你老爸也追过瞪羚
I thought you wanted to be wild.  Your dad chased gazelles.
如果他在我们这年纪 一定会跟我们一起大玩特玩
Yeah, if he were our age, he would so be rockin' out with us.
他一定会把他们扑倒 把他们当成…
He'd be in there, runnin' 'em down like they were...
瞪羚  没错，瞪羚之类的
Gazelles.  Yeah, gazelles or somethin'.
准备好了吗？
Ready, man?
最好还是不要啦
We'd better not.
干吗？你打算阻止我们吗？
Oh, yeah? Are you gonna stop us?
大伙儿  上吧
Guys, guys.  Here we go!
整场比赛的输赢 就看这一次
The whole series comes down to this throw!
我俩没有明天 不是你死就是我亡
There's no tomorrow! It's do or die!
你们懂我的意思啦
Ya know what I mean.
大伙儿，我知道我们落后 不过我们会反败为胜
Guys, I know we're down, but we're gonna pull this out
因为我们要使出
'cause we're gonna use...
…秘密绝招  秘密绝招！
...the secret play.  The secret play!
大伙儿，猜怎么着？ 我们要用秘密绝招耶
Hey, everybody, guess what? We're gonna use the secret play!
赖瑞 秘密绝招最重要的一件事
Larry, the first part of the secret play
就是要保守秘密
is keeping it secret.
好啦  跟着我
OK.  Follow my lead.
大家要加倍努力
I'm going to need a double effort from everybody.
没问题，队长 三倍努力都行
Absolutely, captain. Triple effort if you want, sir.
很好，预备…  散开
Good. Ready, and...  Break!
安静
Quiet.
我数到三 一、二…
On three, dude. One, two...
不！
No!
这下被你搞砸了，雷恩
Now you did it, Ryan.
你够狠吗，阿诺？
Feelin' mean, Donald?
放马过来吧
Bring it on!
各位，山大王的压力很大
Folks, there's pressure on the big guy!
准备好了吗，BJ？  好了
Ready, Bridget?  Ready.
斑尼，你呢？  准备好了
Ready, Benny?  Ready!
山大王，可惜你那小鬼 没来看你输得惨兮兮
Samson, it's a shame your little brat isn't here to see you lose.
我撑不下去了
I can't... hold it!
噢，不，你在干吗？
Oh, no! What are you doin'?
山大王要丢了 大家看看他有多猛
And here comes Samson. Look at that guy.
他是不是帅呆了？
Is he a beauty or what?
赖瑞！BJ！快刷！
Larry! Bridget! Sweep!
真有一套
What a recovery!
他派BJ和赖瑞上场
He's sendin' in Bridget and Larry to do the job!
刷快点，赖瑞！ 快刷，快刷！
Sweep faster, Larry! Sweep, sweep!
我在刷呀  加油
I am!  Come on, man!
企鹅队派出他们的王牌维特
Team Penguin is sending their ace, Victor...
小心，维特  你自己才要小心
Watch it, Victor!  Watch it yourself, see?
尼啾，情况如何？
Nigel, how are we looking?
大伙儿，情况不妙  刷刷刷，刷刷刷
This could be trouble, folks!  Sweep, sweep, sweep.
这是作弊，你们死定了
This is cheating and you will die for this.
我听不到，尼啾
I can't hear you, Nigel.
往左一点点
Move left a bit...
很好，往左然后用力一击
OK. Move left and hit!
赖瑞，不要  大力一挥
Larry, no!  Tallyho!
好漂亮的动作
What a move!
各位，再过几寸 这将是冰龟大赛
Folks, we are inches away from the greatest upset
史上最精采的反败为胜
in turtle-curling history!
糟了，我不敢相信我看到的  不！
Oh, no! I can't believe my eyes!  No!
看来山大王凸槌了
Looks like Samson might have choked!
漂亮  好耶
Nice!  Yes!
真是不可思议
Unbelievable!
山大王和他的队友 一举夺下冠军
Samson and his team have clinched the title!
等等，我话说的太早了  搞什么鬼？
No, wait! I've called it too soon!  What the heck?
企鹅队赢了 他们首度夺下冠军
The penguins have done it! They're zoo champs for the first time!
群兽逃窜？群兽逃窜！
Stampede? Stampede!
拜托，停下来
Please! Stop!
小心
Watch out!
兄弟，我们被逮到了
Dude. Busted.
事情大条了
Catastrophic.
我说过会来看比赛
Told you I'd come to the game.
你觉得这样很好玩？
You think this is funny?
你差点把动物园的动物都害惨
You just endangered everyone in the zoo!
抱歉  你为什么道歉？
I'm sorry.  For what?
为了追赶瞪羚 还是害我们输掉比赛？
Chasing the gazelles or costing us the game?
你只会躲在树上垂头丧气
All you do is sit up in your tree and sulk.
如果你…  你到底怎么啦？
If you just...  What's the problem?
只因为你不会吼吗？
Is all this because you can't roar?
雷恩，我不是故意的
Ryan, I didn't mean that.
你知道我为什么躲在树上 成天垂头丧气吗？
Know what I'm doing when I'm sulking in my tree?
我真希望万兽之王 山大王不是我老爸
I'm thinking how great it would be if Samson the Wild wasn't my father.
雷恩，我不是…
Ryan, I didn't...
这样大家就不会瞧不起 我这个逊脚雷恩
'Cause it would make being Ryan the Lame a lot easier.
雷恩，对不起
Ryan, I'm sorry.
雷恩，求求你
Ryan! Please don't...
…别走
...leave.
拜了，雷恩 多谢你来看比赛
Bye, Ryan! Thanks for coming to the game.
你还怕他不来
And you were worried he wouldn't show up.
真是的 没有人肯听松鼠的话
Not good. No one listens to the squirrel.
我不知道该怎么办，斑尼
I don't know what to do anymore, Benny.
我什么方法都试过了  真的吗？
I've tried everything.  Everything?
你什么方法都试过？  你想说什么？
You tried everything?  What are you saying?
我只想说你要告诉他实话
I'm saying you have to tell him the truth.
我不能说实话，斑尼
I don't think I could do that, Benny.
我是说…
I mean...
他知道真相后会怎么想？
What's he gonna think of me when he finds out?
我也不知道
I don't know.
不过如果你不告诉他
But if you don't tell him...
就会失去这个儿子
...you're gonna lose him, Sammy.
（勇猛骄傲，野性大发）
绿色箱子
The green boxes.
（野性大发）
（禁区，请勿进入）
全都装上去了
OK, they're all loaded up!
你以为我不知道吗？  走吧
You don't think I know that?  Get movin'!
我改变主意了，我不想走
I changed my mind! I don't wanna go!
救命啊！
Help!
雷恩
Ryan.
救救我！
Help me!
小心！
Watch out!
山大王！
Sam!
等等我们  爸！
Wait for us!  Dad!
雷恩！  爸！
Ryan!  Dad!
别让他们把我带走
Don't let them take me!
不！  雷恩！
No!  Ryan!
救命啊！
Help!
不！  爸，快来救我
No!  Dad! Help me!
雷恩！
Ryan!
斑尼，我们要追踪那辆卡车  收到
Benny, we need that truck followed.  Check.
快去找…鸽子
Get me... the pigeons.
我要一对六点
I am wanting snake eyes!
来呀，宝贝
Come on, baby.
快丢呀
Come on, just throw it.
谢了
Thanks.
阿山，你是史上最大的输家
Hamir! You are the great loser of all time!
我到底该奉献什么给你呢？
What offerings must I make, I wonder?
阿山！阿山！
Hamir! Hamir!
冷静一点
Get a grip on yourself!
斑尼，我要等到礼拜五 才能把钱还给你
Benny! I am needing till Friday before I am paying you back!
不是啦，是雷恩
No, no. It's Ryan.
他被装进绿色箱子 被他们带走了
He's in one of those green boxes and they took it away!
我们一定要找到他
We've got to find him!
事情大条了，情况不妙
That is not good! Not good at all!
我知道啦
I know! I know!
我正在告诉他 你们这些起肖的鸽子
I am telling him, you crazy pigeon!
绿色箱子会被带到大海
The green boxes go to the big water
海上有一个 头上有尖刺的女雕像
where stiff lady with spikes on her head...
阿山，我听不懂  尖刺呀！
Hamir? I can't understand...  Spikes!
告诉我绿色箱子去哪里
Just tell me where the green boxes go.
女雕像？尖刺？
Stiff lady, spikies?
没错，就像我太太说的
Yes, like my wife says,
卡车把他们载到她那里
the truck takes them to her! To her!
虽然我只喜欢报喜不报忧 不过我有更多坏消息
Though I hate telling bad news, there is more bad news to tell.
天一亮，绿色箱子 就要搭船离开永远不会回来
When the sun rises, the green boxes leave on boat-boat and never return!
（动物园到非洲拯救行动）
真的很遗憾，我很难过
I am sorry for this. I really am.
有人在吗？
Hello?
惨了，情况不妙
No. Not good. Not good.
你老是这么说
You always say that.
我老是这么说，可是没人肯听
I keep on sayin' it. No one's listenin'.
就像一张跳针的老唱片
Like a broken record here.
山大王，我们几时出发？
OK. When do we leave, Sammy?
对啊，我们几时出发？
Yeah, when do we leave?
不是我们，只有我 搞清楚
It's not "we." It's me. Let's make this clear.
这是拯救行动 要去的只有我一个
This is now a rescue mission and I am the only one going.
我们也要去，我们都不怕
We'll come too! We're not afraid.
对吧，大伙儿？
Are we, guys?
怕？当然不怕罗
Afraid? No.
你们知道无尾熊嘛 我们只会发抖
You know koalas. More like "scared of things."
雷恩就像咱们自己的小孩
Ryan's like a cub to all of us.
不过看来我这辈子 是不会有自己的小孩了
Not that I'll ever have one of my own at this rate.
有一只有名的无尾熊说过
You know, there's that famous... A koala once said,
「我们要用…水蜜桃打他们」
"We will fight them... with peaches."
是哦，言归正传
Yeah. Anyway.
不管怎样，我们都要帮忙  你们要跟我来？好吧
So we're helping, whatever it takes.  You want to leave with me? OK.
如果你们不怕被猎捕、射杀
If you don't mind being hunted down, shot at...
…被做成标本的话  好吧
...stuffed...  OK!
或是更惨的事，那就来吧
...or worse, then fine.
我经常做的恶梦就是 被剥皮和去斑
I have a recurring nightmare about taxidermy and spot remover.
他们想抓到我门儿都没有 我跑得超快的
Well, they have to catch us before they can stuff us and I'm fast.
除了我谁都不能去，了吗？
Nobody's leaving but me. Got it?
你才是老大  没错
You're the boss.  You bet.
你是万兽之王嘛  一点也没错
You got the big hair.  Absolutely.
好耶，好伎俩，山大王
Yeah, that's good, Sammy.
先把最弱的成员踢掉
Hey, way to weed out the weak links.
他们不会碍事了 你有什么计划？
Now that they're out of the picture, what's the plan?
（纽约市立动物园）
你放一百万个心，老大
Don't worry about a thing, big guy.
我早就想好了
I got it all taken care of.
我对这城市
I know this city...
…了若指掌
...like the back of my paw.
咱们在第五大道下车 先左转两次，再右转两次
We ditch this truck at Fifth Avenue, couple lefts, couple rights,
然后过了百老汇
bada-boom, past Broadway and...
…就到了
You're there!
你跑来这儿干吗？
What are you doing here?
什么？  我们是来帮你找到雷恩
What?  We're going to help you find Ryan!
她说 「我们要帮你找到雷恩」
She said, "We're gonna help you find Ryan."
太好了  喂，大伙儿
Oh, great.  Hey, guys.
我的屁眼塞了爆米花
I've got popcorn up my bum.
（爆米花）
Do I look trashy in this?
我穿这样会不会很俗？
好吧，这是我的…
OK, here's my...
这是我的通盘计划 我们到底要去哪儿呀？
Here's my overall plan. Where are we going?
天亮之前如果不救出雷恩 他就永远不会回来
I only have until sunrise before Ryan is taken away forever!
现在我还要担心你们三个？
And now I have to worry about you three?
好吧，斑尼，我们几时下车？
All right, fine. When do we get off of this thing, Benny?
斑尼也在这里？
Benny's here?
是啊，他在那里
Yeah, he's right there.
斑尼？
Benny?
斑尼！
Benny!
这下好了，现在怎么办？
Great. Now what am I gonna do?
大伙儿，我们应该蹲下来
Guys! Guys! I think we should duck!
她说什么？
What is she saying?
她说「蹲下来」
She said, "Duck down!"
蹲下来
Duck!
我可没心情玩动手动脚
I am not in the mood for a game of footsie
或是动蹄动掌的游戏
or hoofsie or pawsie or...
那不是我的脚掌，是这玩意儿
That wasn't my paw. It was this!
我不是偷来的，是借来了
I didn't steal it. I borrowed it.
可以照亮找到雷恩的路
It'll light the way to Ryan.
（玩具反斗城）
（纽约市立动物园 生物研究中心）
墙壁在动耶
The walls are moving.
对哦，墙壁…
Right, right. The walls...
墙壁在动！
The walls are moving!
赖瑞，憋住气
Larry, hold your breath!
赖瑞，保持这样
Larry, stay straight!
大家出去！
Everybody out!
别紧张，我们只要…
All right, don't panic. What we've got to do...
情况很不妙，山大王！
This is definitely not good. Samson!
把你的脚伸出来  救命啊！
Give me your hoof!  Help!
赖瑞！
Larry!
垃圾！它活过来了！
The garbage! It lives!
（每平方寸）
大伙儿？
Guys?
有人在吗？ 我吓呆了
OK, anybody? I'm freakin' out.
你们在等什么？  有人吗？
What's the hold up?  Hello?
我们在这里，尼啾
We're over here, Nigel.
好，我马上来
Right. I'll be there in a minute.
用力想，斑尼说什么？
Think. What did Benny say?
先左转两次，再右转两次
Couple of lefts, couple of rights.
BJ，你看得到绿色女士吗？
Bridget, can you see the green lady?
我正在看，我正在看
I'm looking, I'm looking,
不过我什么也看不到
but I can't see over anything for a change.
你们到底在哪里？ 另一个大陆吗？
How far are you away? You in a different continent?
赖瑞，那是你吗？
Is that you, Larry?
我在上面，尼啾
Up here, Nige.
你这条蛇的毛还真多耶
You're a very furry snake.
大伙儿，不要太引人注目
Guys... We don't want to draw attention to ourselves.
小狗狗，山大王 你一定觉得很好玩
Dogs. This should be fun for you, Samson.
尼啾，抓住BJ！
Nigel! Grab Bridget!
什么？  快跑呀！
What?  Run!
我要吐了，我要吐了
I'm gonna throw up! I'm gonna throw up!
你不是应该 把他们撕成碎片吗？
Shouldn't you be tearing them to shreds?
这是计划的一部份 这一招叫赛伦盖提脱逃术
All part of the plan. This maneuver's known as the Serengeti Slip.
「掠食动物教战手册」第十页
Page ten of the Predator's Playbook.
现在怎么办？
What next?
第十一页？
Page 11?
尽管笑吧，杂种狗
Go on, you mutts!
笨狗狗，我们大可以教训你们
Stupid dogs, we could've taken you.
教你们…跳迪斯可
Taken you to a... To a disco!
赖瑞，想想办法
Larry, improvise!
赖瑞，你愈帮愈忙  好吧
Larry, that's not helping.  OK.
你们这些逊狗以为很会狗叫？ 山大王可是会狮子吼耶
You dogs think you got bark? Well, Samson's got roar!
让他们瞧瞧你的厉害  秀出你的本领
Show 'em, Sam.  Dig deep, Samson.
你是一头狮子，大显神威吧
You're a lion. Be a lion.
看看那家伙
Look at that guy!
山大王，他们口吐白沫
Sam, they are frothing at the mouth.
好吧
OK...
赖瑞，卷起来  收到
Larry, coil!  Check!
山大王  这是随机应变，快跳啊
Sam!  I improvised. Now jump!
跳下去？  对
Down there?  Yes!
我们要走了哦，赖瑞
We're leaving, Larry!
山大王，我只想问你哦 你碰到刚才那些狗
Teensy question, Samson. With those dogs up there,
为什么不像你在 大草原那样对付他们？
why didn't you just do what you did in the wild?
你知道嘛 冲上去把他们扑倒
You know, lionize 'em or lionate them
把他们吓得皮皮挫？
or lionify them?
我没时间和小狗穷磨菇
I don't have time to fight dogs, Bridget.
我们得找到雷恩，记得吗？
We have to find Ryan, remember?
这是什么鬼地方？
What is this stinky place?
这地方
Lt...
…看起来是人类洗澡的地方
...appears to be a human bathing area.
你是说人类 不是把自己舔干净？
You mean humans don't lick themselves clean?
真恶心
Disgusting!
他们真是无药可救 很难想像他们在统治世界
They're hopeless. It is hard to believe they are at the top of the food chain.
我无法想像 他们从不把自己舔干净
I can't imagine beginning the day without licking myself.
我不是在催你哦 不过你有计划吗？
No hurry, but is there a plan?
当然有罗
Of course there's a plan.
我们沿着这条水道到大海
We follow this water to the big water,
然后找到那个…
and then we find the lady with...
赖瑞，如果不是你肚子在叫 就是你肚子里有东西在叫
Larry, either your stomach is growling or something in it is growling.
又不是我
Wasn't me.
干吗？
What?
干得好，尼啾  哇塞，双胞胎耶
Smooth move, Nigel!  Oh, boy! Twins!
山大王，快一点 这两个家伙
OK, Sammy, hurry it up now, 'cause these guys
…好像肚子很饿
are seeming to have acid reflux or something!
大伙儿冷静点
Everybody... stay calm.
冷静？  不好了
Calm?  Not good.
喂，吓你们的啦
Yo. Boo!
你和你的麻吉们好像
I'm gonna say, it looks like you and your crew here
…离你们的家园太远了吧
are a little far from your borough.
离你们的家园太远了  好好笑哦
Far from your borough! I love it.
我们要去大海那边
We're going to the big water.
尼啾，比一比我们要找什么
Nigel, show them what we're looking for.
像这样吗？  她是用右手拿
Like this?  I think it's in her right hand.
她不是蓝色的吗？  我不会变色
And isn't she blue?  I can't do blue.
你不知道吧？  完全没印象
No idea. You?  Doesn't even register.
你比得超逊的  不然就比…
You're battin' zero, kid.  Do the thing with...
拜托你快点决定
Make your bloody mind up.
头上有尖刺的那个女巨人
The big female with the spikes on her melon!
他们是观光客
They're tourists.
观光客，听好了 你们得去炮台公园
All right, tourists, listen up. Ya gotta get to Battery Park.
先钻进百老汇的排水沟
First take the Broadway culvert.
钻进百老汇的排水沟？  那有什么问题？
Down the Broadway culvert?  What's wrong with that?
他们会在废水处理厂迷路  少来了
They get lost at the sewage plant!  Get outta here!
你在说什么呀？  要不然要怎么走？
What are you talking about?  How would you send 'em?
你指的路不对啦
You're sendin' 'em the wrong way!
华尔街在修路 排水沟被堵住了
The Wall Street culvert is blocked with construction.
那也对  好吧
That is true.  All right.
两位，你们到底帮不帮忙？
Guys, you gonna help or not?
当然帮忙罗 我们一定会帮到底
Yeah, sure. Of course we're gonna help ya's.
咱们都是一家人，对吧？
We're one big family, right?
除了那个家伙 他把我给吓…
Except for that guy there. He scares the...
你有完没完呀，卡麦？
You done runnin' your mouth yet, Carmine? Are ya?
抱歉，他曾经被冲下马桶 到现在还余悸犹存
I apologize. He never got over being flushed down the toilet.
是啊
Yeah.
跟我来，你们在这里 肯定活不了十分钟
Follow me, 'cause you four won't last ten minutes in this neighborhood.
这地方是大草原
It's a jungle down here.
史旦，你知道他是谁吗？  什么？不知道
Stan, you know who that is?  What? No.
他是会说话的无尾熊
That's one of them talkin' kawana bears!
你好吗？
How ya doing?
我超可爱的，我喜欢你
I'm so cuddly! I like you!
我看过一大堆无尾熊玩偶 从下水道流下来
I've seen a lot of those things floatin' here in the sewer.
超好笑的 你害我笑到不行
That's good! You're makin' me laugh over here.
等等我
Just wait for me!
我们来对地方了吗？
Are we in the right place?
只要没有那两只搞笑的鳄鱼
Any place without two hilarious alligators
应该就对了
seems a move in the right direction.
山大王，你看到什么吗？  看到了
Sam, do you see anything up there?  I sure do.
她就在那里 就跟阿山说的一样
Well, well, well. There she is, like Hamir said.
天亮了 咱们的时间不多了
And it's sunrise, which means we're a tad short on time.
大伙儿，听好 雷恩被关在绿色箱子
Guys, look. We know the box Ryan's in is green.
一定就在这附近 我要你们…
It's gotta be around here, so I need you to...
知道啦，看到箱子就大叫
Yeah. So we should shout out if we see a box
就像那边的那些箱子
that looks like the ones over there.
还没运走，我们追得回来
It hasn't left yet! We can make it!
快走吧  抓紧了，赖瑞
Let's go!  Hold on, Larry!
往哪儿走？  对啊，哪儿？
Which way now?  Yeah, which way?
快跑！
Run!
不！
No!
雷恩在那上面
Ryan's on that thing!
我们一定要阻止它
We've got to stop it!
不行啦，山大王  我不管
We can't, Sam!  I don't care!
不行啦，你会淹死的 山大王！
No, Sammy, you'll drown!  Sam!
我又失败了
I failed. Again.
我只失败过这么一次
I only count one failure.
彻底的大失败 不过就这么一次
It's big, but it's just one.
再见了，雷恩 我们会很想念你
Goodbye, Ryan. We're gonna miss ya.
山大王！  这到底是怎么回事？
Samson!  What on earth is going on?
那是个人类 他不是替动物园工作
It's a human and I do not think he works for the zoo.
也许现在应该要随机应变
Perhaps now is a good time to improvise.
什么？
What?
太好了，解决了一个问题
Great! One problem down...
棒呆了
Far out.
酷哦
Cool.
又遇上一个大灾难
One disaster to go.
你在干什么？ 我们要撞上另一艘船了
What are you doing? We're headed for the other boat!
这要怎么开呀？ 谁知道要怎么开船？
How do we steer? Who knows how to steer?
谁都不会 我们只是动物，这下可好了
None of us. We're animals. Great!
等等，赖瑞，再做一次  做什么？
Hold on, Larry. Do that again.  Do what?
你刚才那样 不过这次要反方向
Whatever you just did, but the opposite!
我不知道反方向是哪里
But I don't know my opposites!
不对，像这样
No, Larry, like this!
我好像学会了
I think I've got it.
很简单嘛
Well, that was easy.
天啊，谁有尤加利叶？ 我要擦屁屁
Oh, dear. Has anyone got any eucalyptus wipes?
这并不难嘛
This isn't so difficult.
我是大海的狮王
I'm the lion of the sea!
干得好
Well done, sir.
你是咱们的队长 现在是这艘船的船长
Captain of our team and now captain of this vessel.
你超棒的
You're brilliant.
我不想扫兴 不过在一片混乱中
I hate to be Miss Negative, but in this melee,
我们把雷恩的船追丢了
we seem to have lost Ryan's boat.
什么？啥都没有？  对，它不见了
What, nothing?  Nothing. He's gone.
不
No.
那里，尼森，绿色箱子
There! Nelson! The green boxes!
你确定？  我的麻吉在那里
You're sure, eh?  And there's my buddies!
还有我的最爱
And my love!
我们下去吧
Let's go in!
我们要背着太阳走  不，要朝着太阳往北走
We'll head away from the sun.  No, towards the sun. To the north.
右舷…左舷
Starboard... Leftboard.
跟着我的指头就对了
Just follow my finger.
拜托，就算答案从天而降
Please. You guys wouldn't know the answer
打到你们头上 你们也不会知道
if it fell from the sky and hit you in the head.
天啊，有一只蝙蝠
Oh, my! It's a bat! It's a bat!
快把他弄掉，快弄掉
Get it off me! Get it off me!
斑尼！  斑尼？
Benny!  Benny?
天鹅！
Geese!
你没事吧？  没事，我的公主
Are you all right?  Yes, my princess.
斑尼，你来了
Benny, you made it!
你们是我的好朋友 好朋友应该团结一致
You're my best friend. Best friends should stick together.
就算不怎么好的朋友也要
Even not-so-best friends,
竟然把我 从急驶的垃圾车上踢下去
who knock you off a speeding garbage truck.
对不起啦 不过我求他们回去找你
Excuse me, but I begged them to go back and get you.
这一点我要说清楚哦
Just so you know.
斑尼，你在上面 看得到雷恩的船吗？
Benny, could you see Ryan's boat from up there?
我正好看到它往那里走
Well, it just so happens I saw it heading that way.
而且我们很幸运
And we're in luck!
你们好吗？  加拿大野雁
How's it goin', eh?  Canadian geese!
勇闯天涯旅行专家
Experts at intercontinental travel.
嗨，小鸟，我问你哦
Hey, birdie, OK,
加拿大的移民政策 是不是对无尾熊特别宽待？
is it true that Canada has lax immigration policies for koalas?
我问就好 我儿子被带走了
I'll take it from here. My son's out there.
我们真的需要你们帮忙 你们能带我们找到那艘船吗？
We really need your help. Can you lead us to that boat?
没问题，跟着我们就行了
No problem, eh? Just follow us and Bob's your uncle.
不要落后太远，好吗？
Try not to lag too far behind, eh?
斑尼，谢了
Hey, Benny, thanks.
对了，你掉下去的时候 BJ很担心你哦
And FYI, Bridget was very concerned when you fell off the truck.
我打赌你一定不知道 我会骑野雁，对吧？
Bet you didn't know I could ride geese, did you?
厉害吧？  拜托
Bareback.  Oh, brother.
山大王？ 我们要去大草原吗？
Sammy? We going to the wild now?
应该是吧，赖瑞
I think we are, Larry.
（纽约大西洋）
我受不了了
I can't take it anymore.
他在耍我们，你们听
He's taunting us! Listen!
别再笑我们了，臭太阳
Stop laughing at us, you solar twit!
山大王船长 有没有冰淇淋吃？
Captain Bligh, sir! Are the ice cream cones ready?
船员就快要发动叛变了
The crew, they're on the verge of mutiny.
尼啾，拜托
Nigel, please.
不给我们吃冰淇淋
If you don't give us ice creams pretty quick,
我们就要逼你跳进大海
you're gonna walk the plank, sir!
尼啾  我不管我会不会淹死
Nigel.  I don't care if I drown,
我只想马上离开这艘幽灵船
I'm getting off this death cruise right now.
冰山！ 我要和这艘船共生死
Iceberg! Permission to go down with the ship, sir.
等一下，这话我收回
Hang on! Stuff that!
快跑啊！游泳！
Run! Swim!
尼啾？
Nigel?
瞧，我是海星耶
Look, I'm a starfish.
大伙儿，你们看
Guys, look.
天啊，你一定觉得 花了一辈子才到
Gosh. Must feel like a lifetime since you've been here.
是啊，一辈子
Yeah... a lifetime.
搞什么鬼？
What the heck?
哇，你们看
Wow! Look!
他们把绿色箱子放回大草原
They're releasing the green boxes back into the wild.
赖瑞  大伙儿
Larry.  Guys,
他们把动物又装进绿色箱子
they're putting animals inside the green boxes.
我搞不懂为什么
I just can't figure out why.
那是通往另一个空间的通道
It's a tunnel to another dimension, can't you see?
他们先进去…  这家伙是谁？
They go in...  Who is this guy?
没关系，尼啾
It's all right, Nigel.
你想这跟那玩意有关吗？
Think it has anything to do with that?
等一下，如果我不是饿昏了头 就是赖瑞说的有道理
Hang on a second. Either I'm starving or Larry is making sense.
你说得对 有人在拯救那些动物
You're right. Those animals are being rescued.
雷恩？
Ryan?
雷恩！
Ryan!
噢，不！
Oh, no!
雷恩！
Ryan!
我们要快一点
We've got to move fast!
雷恩！
Ryan!
雷恩！雷恩！
Ryan! Ryan!
雷恩！ 儿子，你在哪里？
Ryan! Where are you, buddy?
雷恩！
Ryan!
我不敢相信  山大王
I can't believe it!  Samson!
我离他这么近，他就在那里
I was so close. He was right there!
现在找不到他了  过来
We'll never find him now!  Come here!
冷静一点，用你的直觉
Will you get a hold of yourself? Use your instincts.
我不想再跑了
I don't want to run anymore.
那敢情好，老实说 你需要好一点的运动内衣
Good. 'Cause frankly, you need a good sports bra.
雷恩？  一切都能搞定
Ryan?  Everything's under control.
失败只是暂时的  我闻到了
Temporary setback.  I got it.
我闻到雷恩的味道  他闻到了？
I got Ryan's scent!  He got it?
他闻到了耶！快走吧！
I mean, he got it! Let's go!
万岁！  等等我们！
Hooray!  Wait for us!
我不是赛跑选手 我需要一辆车
I'm not designed for this! I want a car.
大伙儿，我找到他了 雷恩！
Hey, guys, I found him! Ryan!
你们不敲门的吗？
Doesn't anyone knock anymore?
我儿子呢？ 他有没有来过这里？
Where's my son? Did he come through here?
对哦，我想起来了 他是来过这里，哈罗
Yeah, now that I think about it, he did come through here. Hello?
出来吧，小狮子 你老爸来了
Come on out, baby lion! Your dad's here!
有没有看到 这儿有一大堆狮子
Well, what do you know? There's a whole pride of lions here!
臭死了 我以为你闻到雷恩的味道
Funky. I was under the impression you had Ryan's scent,
不是这个臭得要命的家伙
not this olfactory insult.
我…
I...
我本来闻到雷恩的味道 不过我的掠食动物本能发作
I had Ryan's scent, but my predator instincts must've kicked in since,
因为我有好久没吃东西了
you know, I haven't eaten for a while.
一点也没错
Exactly!
你永远不知道 掠食动物的本能几时发作
You never know when those instincts are gonna kick in.
太好了，棒呆了
Excellent. Fantastic!
我们终于要看到 传奇的山大王发威
We get to see the legend in action.
我也很想呀，不过没时间了
I'd love to, but we just don't have time.
当然有时间，山大王
We got the time, Sammy. Just...
你先这样，然后再这样
And then you do this. And then this bit.
一口把他撕裂
Rip him apart!
超恐怖的
The horror.
我不忍心看，不过一定要看
I can't bear to watch! But I have to.
走吧，快走吧
Go on. Get out of here.
山大王把晚餐放走了  真是的
The legend dropped his dinner.  Oh, boy.
怎么了？ 我不够好，你不屑吃我？
What's wrong? I'm not good enough for you to eat?
不是啦，我只是对疯子过敏
No. It's just I'm allergic to nuts.
我了了，你要先耍我，是吗？
Now I get it. You're gonna toy with me?
先打我几下，然后放我走 趁我戒心解除了再扑上来？
Beat me up a little, then pounce when I get my hopes up?
好刺激哦
How exciting.
来吧，雷恩应该就在附近
Come on, guys. Ryan can't be far.
我还没说完耶 我可是顶极佳肴哦
Hey! I'm not finished with you! I am a delicacy.
我的肉吃起来有果香和木头香
My flesh has fruity wood notes!
说话小心点，开胃菜 他可是万兽之王山大王
Watch it, you little hors d'oeuvre. That's Samson the Wild.
他是万兽之王？
You call this wild?
我看他是只猫吧 一只又肥又弱的病猫
This is a cat! A big, fat, tame pussycat!
好了，够了  病猫在吓唬我耶
OK, that's enough!  The pussycat hissed at me!
也许我应该躲在无尾熊后面 让他保护我
Maybe I should hide behind the koala for protection.
这样好了 你要不要赏我几巴掌？
While we're at it, could you slap me in the face?
不要，你是笨蛋吗？
No. What are you, a twit?
别理他  算了，我要闪了
Ignore him.  Don't bother! I'm leaving.
你是个怪胎  快逃命啊！
You're weird.  Run for your lives!
吃斋念佛的狮子来了！
It's a lion with moral issues!
我也受够你们了
And I've had it with you too!
多谢你们破坏我今天的心情
Thanks a lot for wrecking my day!
我有个小疑问
Teensy question.
这算是问题也算是批评
Or more like a... a sort of a query meets a statement.
刚才那只蹄兔
That hyrax back there?
你好像不太忍心吃他耶
It was sort of like you couldn't eat him.
是啊，还有那些狗 你也没有对他们大开吃戒
Yeah, and what about those dogs? There was no munching there, either.
要不是我很了解你 我会以为你是…
If I didn't know any better, I'd say that you're...
…素食动物  才不是
A vegetarian?  Nope.
我不是那个意思啦  你本来想说的是…
That's not what I was going to say.  You were going to say...
你好像…  你好像不是来自…
It's almost like...  You're not from...
大草原？
The wild?
没错，我不是来自大草原
Well, you're right. I'm not from the wild.
什么？
What?
我是个冒牌货
I'm just a phony.
老实说，我保护不了你们
Truth is I can't protect you out here.
你们赶快回到船上
Please just go back to the boat.
我得去找我儿子
I've got to find my son.
难道我们在危险的大草原 要靠八寸高的松鼠保护吗？
Tell me we're not in a dangerous jungle with an 8-inch squirrel protecting us.
其实我是九寸高 除此之外，你说得对
Actually, I'm nine inches, but other than that, yes.
所以这代表…
So that means...
我们死定了！
We are going to die!
大伙儿！
Hey, guys! Guys!
你们三个冷静一点，好吗？
Will the three of you calm down?
他怎么能骗我们？
How could he lie to us?
我们是他最好的朋友耶  是啊
We're his best friends.  Sure.
也许他不想说出实话 所以才骗我们
Maybe he lied 'cause he didn't want to tell us the truth.
好吧，不管怎样
OK, yeah, whatever. Whatever.
我们回船上去吧
Let's just go back to the boat, then.
野性大发、所向无敌… 胡说八道
The fierce, the proud, the wild... Rubbish!
等等，等等 你们要去哪里？
But wait, wait, wait, wait! Wait! Where you goin'?
站住，站住
Stop right there! Stop!
BJ，如果你走了，我就…
Bridget, if you go, I'm...
我就跟你分手
I'm breaking up with you.
我们从来就没有在一起过
We were never going out in the first place.
那我们就暂时分开一阵子
Then we're taking a break.
尼啾！  好啦！
Nigel!  All right!
听好
Hey, listen!
我知道你们很害怕 至少我们可以互相照应
I know you're scared. But at least we got each other.
山大王就孤零零一个
Sammy's got nobody. He's out there all alone.
而且…雷恩也是
And... so is Ryan.
好吧，专心一点
OK, OK, focus, Samson.
他应该就在这附近 你一定会找到他
He's got to be out there somewhere. You'll find him.
这地方会有多大，对吧？
I mean, how big can this place be, anyway?
雷恩！
Ryan!
嗨，小朋友 你也迷路了吗？
Hey there, little fella. You're lost too, huh?
你让我想到家乡的同伴
You remind me of my buddy back home.
这只凶猛嗜血的野兽
A bloodthirsty monster!
哪里？哪里？
Where? Where?
他是掠食猛兽 离我的宝贝孩子远一点
He's a killer! Get away from my baby!
女士，冷静点
Calm down, lady!
快来救我的孩子呀
Won't anyone save my baby?
拜了
Bye-bye.
雷恩！雷恩！
Ryan! Ryan!
山大王！
Sammy!
我根本不适合野外生活
I wasn't meant for the wild.
我天生气质出众、动作优雅
I was made to nibble and be elegant
我在儿童绘本总是美丽大方
and to appear in children's books as the letter G.
别紧张，这里并不可怕
Come on, this isn't scary, is it?
只有树叶和藤蔓还有…
It's just leaves and vines and...
那是我的脚
Oh, that's my foot.
尼啾，小心后面
Nigel, keep a lookout back there.
你也一样，赖瑞  没问题
You too, Larry!  Okeydokey.
我知道了，好吧
Oh, I see. All right, OK, yeah.
你在跟我打冷战 我才不在乎呢
You're giving me the silent treatment. Like I care.
尼啾，我对你下命令
Nigel! I gave you an order.
你说声「遵命，长官」 会怎样吗？
Would a little "Sir, yes, sir!" kill ya?
尼啾
Nigel.
这样不好笑，尼啾
That's not funny, Nigel.
他不见了，我们完蛋了  尼啾！
He's gone! We're doomed.  Nigel!
先是雷恩，然后是山大王 现在又轮到尼啾
First Ryan, then Samson, and now Nigel!
我觉得动物园比较好
I do believe in zoos.
赖瑞，你在抓狂  是真的，真的
Larry, you're tensing up!  I do, I do, I do.
别紧张，这儿有我在  所以我们才紧张
Don't panic. I'm in charge.  That's why we're panicking!
咱们散开来围一个圈
I say we fan out and circle.
我们是孔雀吗？ 我们又不是扇子，快跑吧
What are we, peacocks? We don't fan, we run.
快逃命啊，大伙儿！
Run for your lives, everybody!
大伙儿，我有个主意 咱们何不问问他们？
Guys, I've got an idea. Why don't we ask them?
放心，他们有蹄
It's OK... They, you see, they got hooves.
这代表他们不吃肉 只吃草
That means they don't hunt. They graze.
可是他们在舔下巴耶
But they're licking their chops.
我对付膝盖怪怪的那个
I'll take the one with the funny knees.
膝盖怪怪的？
The funny knee...?
斑尼，不！
Benny, no!
斑尼？
Benny?
抓住他们
Get them.
退后，对不起
Just, hey, back off. I'm sorry,
我不是那种乱搞的无尾熊
I'm not that kind of koala bear.
是哦
Right.
对不起，你好 很抱歉打扰了你
Excuse me? Hello? Terribly sorry to bother you,
你会说无尾熊语吗？
but do you speak koala? Sprechen Sie koala?
好吧
Right.
拜托你能不能 不要去冒烟的地方？
Could you possibly not go towards the big smoking thing?
朋友，你好 朋友，你好
G'day, mate G'day, mate
在这地方开派对好怪哦
What a strange place for a party.
不错，很有秩序
Very good, very organized.
我能借用厕所吗？
Can I use your toilet?
今天真是个
I'm having a
美好的一天…
Really nice day Really nice day
美好的一天
Really nice day
今天真是个
I'm having a
美好的一天…
Really nice day Really nice day
美好的一天
Really nice day
大家一起来  开怀大笑，开怀大笑
Why don't you all  Tickle away, tickle away
他们是可怕的怪物
They're frighteningly horrible monster beasts...
不过舞跳得还不错
...but they're not bad dancers.
我是小可爱，我爱你
I'm so cuddly I like you
向前踢，向侧踢、向前走
Step-kick, pivot-kick, walk, walk, walk.
今天真是个  美好的一天
I'm having a  Really nice day
噢，不！
Oh, no!
开怀大笑  开怀大笑
Tickle away Tickle away
我是小可爱，我爱你  祝你愉快
I'm so cuddly, I like you Good day
那是什么东西？  我是蛮牛
What is that?  I am Kazar.
领袖、先知
Leader. Prophet.
编舞老师
Choreographer.
因为有你们 我也是肉食动物
And with your help... carnivore!
不！不要吃我！ 我吃的苦够多了！
No! Don't kill me! I've had such a weird life!
这不公平
This is not fair.
我知道了，这是瑜珈营
Oh, I get it. A yoga retreat.
雷恩！
Ryan!
你办得到的，运用本能
You can do this. Use your instincts.
跟随你的直觉
Follow your instincts.
运用本能
Use your instincts.
好吧
OK.
走这里
Down this way.
这里
This way.
小狮子
A lion cub.
我们得向蛮牛报告
We must tell Kazar.
轮到我向他报告  上次是你向他报告
It's my turn to tell him.  You got to last time.
才没有  有，就是你
No, I didn't.  Yes, you did!
多谢各位，不过我得走了
Thank you very much, but I'm afraid I've got to run.
无尾熊像工蜂一样忙碌
Koalas are very busy bees.
我自己出去就可以了
If I could... I'll just buzz along to the door...
数百年来 我们看着我们的同胞
For centuries, we've watched our brethren
死在狮子的利爪之下
perish at the claw of the lion.
今天我们要报一箭之仇
Today, we put our hooves down.
我们再也不要待在 食物链的最底层
No longer will we dwell at the bottom of the food chain.
没错，很有志气
Well, yes. I should say so.
我们有些同胞 不相信你会来带领我们
There were those who doubted that you'd arrive to lead us.
但是我一直都相信预兆
But I always believed in the Omen.
预兆，请你再提醒我一次
The Omen! Right. Remind me again?
多年前的神明指示
Sent down by the gods years ago...
不，又是你
Oh, no! Not you!
我是小可爱，我爱你
I'm so cuddly! I like you!
伟大的神兽
Oh, Great Him,
你必须带领我们从猎物变成
you must lead us in our transformation from prey...
…掠食动物
...to predator.
慢着，我是伟大的神兽？
Hold it. I am the Great Him?
伟大的神兽？  神兽？
The Great Him?  Him.
这都是你的错 没错，都是你啦
So this is all your fault! That's it! You...!
蛮牛！ 蛮牛，别听他的
Kazar!  Kazar! Don't listen to him!
蛮牛，听我说  蛮牛，这里
Kazar! Over here!  Kazar! Over here!
你胆敢打断我拜见神兽
How dare you interrupt my audience with the Great Him!
可是…我们找到一只小狮子
But... but we found a lion cub!
真的假的？  他旁边有一只大狮子吗？
You did?  Was he with a big lion?
有长长的鬃毛？ 其实只是后面很长啦
With big hair? Well, a mullet, really.
伟大的神兽 你带来两头狮子？
Oh, Great Him, you brought two lions with you?
我就像其它神兽一样
Well, like any Great Him,
出门旅行都会带保镳
I travel with an entourage.
放心，伟大的神兽 我会叫布雷把狮子带来
Worry not, Your Himness, I shall have Blag bring the lions here.
这次他最好别搞砸 别像刚刚那样搞砸我的编舞
And he better not screw this up, like you screwed up my dance number!
我只落后了一小音节
I lost count for one verse.
向前踢，向侧踢、向前走
Step-kick, pivot-kick, walk, walk, walk.
我们干吗那么辛苦练舞？
Why do we even bother rehearsing?
好的舞群真的很难找耶
A good chorus line is so hard to put together.
快飞上天呀
Take to the skies!
我们这就飞了
We're taking! We're taking!
快去找到他们  遵命，老大
Find them!  Yes, sir.
把狮子给我带来
Bring us those lions!
众神在庆祝预言终于实现
The gods celebrate the fulfillment of the prophecy.
我们一起用力踏步
We stamp our hooves
赞颂伟大的神兽
in praise of the Great Him!
我的妈啊
Holy moly!
我的妈啊  我的妈啊
Holy moly Holy moly
你是万兽之王
You are our king!
你看，那是谁？
Looky, looky who's there.
惊喜！
Surprise!
不！
No!
抱歉我们来晚了
Sorry we're late for dinner!
逊毙了
That's pathetic!
滚开
Get off!
一点都不痛  住手
That didn't hurt!  Stop!
雷恩！  不！
Ryan!  No!
我来了，儿子
I'm coming, son!
爸？
Dad?
救命啊  咱们快闪吧
Help!  Let's scram!
雷恩！  你怎么会在这里？
Ryan!  What are you doing here?
我不敢相信，我找到你了  你是怎么找到我的？
I can't believe it! I found you.  How'd you find me?
你没事吧？有没有受伤？
Are you all right? Are you hurt?
你的脚掌  我被困在绿色箱子
Your paw.  I got trapped in that box.
没事了，儿子
It's OK, son.
后来我逃出来，逃进丛林
And then I escaped, and I ran into the jungle...
然后这些兀鹰飞来想杀死我
...then those vultures came and tried to kill me.
你一定不怕他们 不过我好怕哦
You wouldn't have been scared. I was.
我有件事要告诉你  什么事？
I have to tell you something.  What?
你听
Listen.
爸，去搞定他们  快跑啊！
Get 'em, Dad!  Run!
快跑！
Run!
爸，你应该追他们
Dad, you should be chasing them!
就像你以前一样  那些只是我说的故事
Like you used to!  Those were just stories!
现在你有机会证明那是真的
But now's your chance to show me for real!
这边
This way!
爸，怎么回事？  先爬到树上再说
Dad? What's goin' on?  Just get up into that tree!
我们甩掉他们了  怎么回事？
I think we lost them.  What's the deal?
他们只是一群逊脚
They're just a bunch of wimpy donkeys!
你大可以把他们打得落花流水
You could kick their rumps!
雷恩，我打不过他们  胆小鬼，给我回来
Ryan, I can't fight them.  You donkey-chickens! Get back here!
雷恩，我打不过他们
Ryan! I can't fight them.
什么意思？
What do you mean?
我小时候
I was young...
还只是只小狮子
...still just a cub.
各位先生女士
Ladies and gentlemen.
可爱的小朋友
Children of all ages.
山大王 别害怕，抬头挺胸
Samson! Swallow that fear and stand tall!
目睹这只小狮子 一生中最重要的一天
Witness the greatest day in our young lion's life!
他张嘴大吼的一天
The day he discovers his roar!
爸，我办不到
Dad, I can't do it!
快去吧
Now, go!
听小山大王发出 震耳欲聋的吼声
Listen as Samson unleashes a roar so mighty,
把一头牛羚震出大草原
it launches a wildebeest clear off the savannah!
小山大王，鼓起勇气
Samson! Dig deep!
我早就知道
I should have known.
如果你生在大草原 就会知道怎么发出吼声
If you'd been born in the wild, you'd know how to roar.
爸？
Dad?
爸！爸！
Dad! Dad!
求求你
Please!
爸
Dad.
当他们把我送到动物园 我不想让任何人知道
When they shipped me to the zoo, I never wanted anyone to know
…我来自哪里 尤其是我最亲近的朋友
where I came from. Especially those closest to me.
我应该早一点告诉你
I should have told you sooner.
可是…你说的那些故事？
But... all those stories you tell?
对不起，雷恩
I'm so sorry, Ryan.
你跟我说的一切都是谎言？
Everything you told me was a lie?
爸！  抓紧了，儿子
Dad!  Hang on, son.
救命啊！
Help!
雷恩！
Ryan!
雷恩！快跑！
Ryan! Run!
想都别想，小鬼
Not so fast, Tigger.
爸！
Dad!
雷恩！
Ryan!
爸！
Dad!
救命啊！  雷恩
Help!  Ryan.
救救我！爸！
Help! Dad!
雷恩  爸，快来救我！
Ryan.  Dad! Help me!
什么？
What?
等等，什么？等等，什么？
Wait! What? What? Wait!
等等…等等…
Wait, wait, wait, wait! Hey! Hey! Hey!
放开我
Get off me!
这是怎么回事？
What is goin' on here?
米田共不会说话 只会像球一样乱滚
Stinky does not speak.  It rolls like a little ball.
慢着，你们以为我是…
Wait. You guys think I'm a...?
闭嘴，米田共  别说话，快滚吧
Achtung, Stinky!  Less talk, more roll.
好  翻滚吧
Ja.  Roll! Roll!
搞什么？
What the...? Hey!
滚米田共能让屁股结实
Rolling the dung is good for tight buns!
我就让你们滚蛋吧
I'll give you something to roll about!
幸好BJ没看到这一幕
It's a good thing Bridget didn't see that!
BJ？赖瑞？ 他们都不见了
Bridget? Larry! They're gone.
我得找到他们
I gotta find them!
不，我得先找到山大王
No! I gotta find Samson first!
不，先找到…
No! First...
山大王，山大王！
Sam. Sam!
BJ！赖瑞！
Bridget! Larry!
雷恩，你还活着
Oh, Ryan! You're alive!
真高兴见到你们
Good to see you guys.
给我抱抱  赖瑞
Where's my hug?  Larry.
来吧  我也很高兴见到你
There it is.  It's good to see you too.
你们跑来这儿干吗？
What are you guys doing here?
我们跟你爸一起来找你
We came here with your father to find you.
他大概正在外头找我们
And he's probably out there right now lookin' for us.
我也希望是这样
I wish he were.
不过牛羚把他撞下悬崖
But some of these wildebeests pushed him off a cliff.
什么？  什么？
What?  What?
我想他活不成了 他没救了
I don't think he made it. I don't see how he could.
噢，雷恩
Oh, Ryan.
很抱歉害你们落到这个下场
I'm sorry I got you into this.
蛮牛，你一定会很喜欢 我们带给你的东西
Kazar, I think you'll be very pleased with what I brought you.
这是什么？ 另一头狮子呢？
What's this? Where's the other lion?
对，我正要告诉你 那里有一座悬崖
Right. Well, I was gonna tell you, there was this cliff and...
你干吗用这种眼神看我？
Why are you looking at me like that?
这是你今天第二次凸槌了 布雷
That's twice you've been out of step today, Blag!
你这大笨蛋
You klutz.
你明明知道 如果不吃掉狮子
You know we can't ascend to the top of the food chain
就升不上食物链顶端
until we eat a lion!
不过至少我可以
Well, at least there'll be enough for my ascension.
那我们怎么办？
What about the rest of us?
向前踢、向侧踢
Step-kick, pivot-kick!
好痛哦，我扭伤了脚
Ouch! I twisted a hoof!
你为他们辛苦为他们忙 他们却伤透了你的心
You work and you work. Then they break your heart.
我的演艺事业完了  准备祭品
There goes my career!  Prepare the sacrifices!
我为什么让他自己去呢？
Why did I let him go off by himself?
他连蚊子都抓不到 更别说是午餐了
He couldn't catch a cold, much less his own lunch.
不过我抓得到你
Bet I could catch you.
拜托
Please.
我的天敌是汽车…什么？
My natural predator is fuel inject... What?
我就知道你没有死 我就知道
I knew you weren't really gone. I knew it!
我早就料到了 咱们还是麻吉，对吧？
Come on, I knew it! We're still buddies, right?
我失去了雷恩
I lost Ryan.
太多敌人了 他被他们抓走了
There were too many. They just took him.
谁？谁把他抓走？
Who? Who took him?
牛羚  那些有蹄的怪胎
Wildebeests.  The freaks with the hooves!
他们也把赖瑞和BJ抓走
They got Larry and Bridget too.
我打不过他们…
Couldn't fight, couldn't...
加油，山大王，你是狮子耶
Come on, Sam. You're a lion.
你是万兽之王的后代
You come from a long line of kings.
没错 也许你不是来自大草原
Yeah, maybe you're not from the wild.
但是你拥有神鬼战士的血统
But fighting's in your blood!
不，我永远不会是真正的狮子
No. I'll never be a real lion.
错了，你是一头真正的狮子
Wrong! You are a real lion.
不管你来自哪里
Doesn't matter where you're from:
动物园、丛林、金鱼缸
Zoo, jungle, goldfish bowl.
内心的勇气才重要
It's what's in here.
你的心决定你是谁
That determines who you are!
至少你都是这么跟你儿子说的
At least, that's what you always told your son.
现在他被抓住了
Now he's out there, Sammy,
而且他需要你
and he needs you.
还有谁能教他怎么吼？
Who else is gonna teach him how to roar?
这就对了，山大王
That's it, Sammy.
很好
That's it.
我们去找我儿子和我的朋友
Let's go find my son... and my friends.
好耶，什么都阻止不了我们
Yeah! Nothing's gonna stop us!
只是我们根本不知道 我们要去哪里
Except that we have no idea where we're going!
跟随你的直觉
Follow your instincts.
那是什么？  我的…直觉
What is that?  My... instincts?
斑尼？  就快到了
Benny?  You're almost there.
我终于搞懂了
That settles it, then.
我妈怀我的时候 一定是喝了太多泳池的水
My mother definitely drank pool water when she was pregnant with me.
斑尼，你看
Benny, look.
有蹄的怪胎
The freaks with hooves!
雷恩在那里面
Ryan's in there.
你不能直接闯进去 那等于是自杀
You can't just barge in. That's suicide!
斑尼，让开  别听那个鼠辈的话
Benny, get out of my way!  Don't listen to the rat.
喂，你骂谁鼠辈？  当然是你罗
Hey, who are you calling a rat?  You, of course.
你会曝露我们的位置  小心我告你哦
You'll give away our position.  I'll have you written up for that!
猪头，你搞砸了我们的伪装 弟兄们！分散！
Fool! You blew our cover! Men! Scatter!
别跑得那么快
Not so fast!
你看我抓到谁，山大老 这是你的狮子本能
Look who I got, Sammy. It's your lion instincts.
你们是谁？
Who are you guys?
我们是谁不重要  我是斗篷，他是迷彩
Our names aren't important.  I'm Cloak. He's Camo.
我们是卧底探员  你们为什么一直误导我？
We're covert agents.  Why have you been leading me around?
这是机密情报  最高机密
That's classified.  Top-secret.
那些牛羚发疯了  斗篷
The wildebeests have gone mad.  Cloak.
我又没告诉他们 我们打算利用他们打败蛮牛…
It's not like I told them our plan is to use them to defeat Kazar's...
听好，告诉我 他们把我儿子抓去了吗？
Listen, just tell me, did they take my son in there?
我不能说 你 一定要说
That's need-to-know.  They did.
他们以为那只无尾熊是神兽  你是史上最逊的卧底探员
They think the koala's a god.  You're the worst covert agent!
是吗？ 那我怎么会这一招？弟兄们！
Oh, yeah? Then why can I do this? Men!
不，住手，山大王！
Hey! No! Stop! Sammy!
猪头，这一招是机密耶  这是秘密，这才是最高机密
Idiot! That maneuver's confidential.  It's secret. This one's confidential.
迷彩  这是机密情报
Cloak!  And this one's restricted.
超级机密情报 最高机密，超级超级机密
Super-secret. Top-secret. This is ultra-secret!
够了，别说了
Enough! No more!
让他们见识超级最高机密 「够了」的招式，没问题！
Show 'em the super-top-secret "no more?" Gotcha!
不！
No!
我有个点子
I got an idea.
神兽到底是谁呀？ 我来对付他
Who is this Great Him, anyway? I'll take him on.
我是女神兽 要让他尝尝我的厉害
I'm the Great Her! I'll show Him a thing or two.
我是天不怕地不怕的纽约客耶
I'm from New York City, for Pete's sake.
天啊
Oh, my.
这一定是在开玩笑
You have got to be kidding me.
尼啾，我不知道你在搞什么鬼
Nigel, I don't know what you're trying to pull,
不过我要海扁你…  住嘴
but I will kick your...  Silence!
你这小王八…
Why, you little...
我叫你住嘴
Silence, again!
你不能跟我说话
You do not speak to me!
尼啾，这是怎么回事？
Nigel, what's the deal?
伟大的神兽 可以准备举行晚宴了吗？
Great Him, shall we prepare the feast?
可以，我们要吃什么？
Yes, we shall! What's on the menu?
他们
Them.
噢，不
Oh, no.
吃朋友就能当神兽 不吃朋友的话…
Eat friends and be god, don't eat friends...
神兽、朋友，神兽、朋友…
God, friends, god, friends. God, I...
真是令人左右为难
Well, that was subtle.
准备升火烤肉
Prepare the meat fire!
等等
Wait!
烤肉不能没有
We cannot cook them without...
…洋葱
...onion!
洋葱…洋葱…
Onions. Onions. Onions.
哇塞，好快哦
Well, that was fast.
开始举行仪式
Let the ritual begin.
走吧
Move it!
我对你超不爽的
I am so mad at you!
等等，我们也需要…帽子
Wait! We also need... hats!
我们没有死刑的派对帽吗？
Do we not have the party hats of death?
我有呀
I've got mine!
而且宴会开始之前 我们都要…
And before the feast, we must all...
搞什么？
What the...?
飘浮
...levitate...
发疯似的旋转
...and spin uncontrollably!
觉得有点想吐
And feel a bit sick.
这玩意要怎么停下来呀？
How do I stop this thing?
大伙儿  斑尼？
Guys.  Benny?
看，一只松鼠  赖瑞
Look, a squirrel!  Larry!
我们有个计划，跟我来
We've got a plan. Follow me.
我们？  我会飞
We?  I can fly!
伟大的神兽 我们臣服在你的威力之下
Oh, Great Him, we are humbled by your power.
臣服吧 只有神兽才会这一招
Be humbled. Only the Great Him can do this!
火山热气  我们的伪装被识破了
Volcanic gas!  Our cover's blown!
严重故障，弃船！
Major malfunction! Abandon ship!
天啊  你也该赶来了
Oh, boy.  Well, about time you got here.
伟大的神兽 这又是另一个奇迹
Great Him, it's another miracle!
你把真正的狮子带来
You've delivered us a real lion!
布雷，你出运了
Blag, your luck has turned.
多亏伟大神兽的帮忙 我们都会升级到食物链顶端
Thanks to the Great Him, we shall all ascend tonight.
尼啾，我们得声东击西
Nigel, we've got to create a distraction.
等一下
Hang on a sec!
我袖里乾坤，藏了一大堆奇迹
I've got miracles comin' out my ears!
预备，退后
Ready? Stand back...
伟大的神兽要对付
...as the Great Me attacks the lion
比我大73倍的狮子
over 73 times my size!
爸？我爸还活着！ 大伙儿，我爸没有死
Dad? My dad's alive! Guys, my dad made it!
雷恩，不！  快点，我要去找他
Ryan, no!  Hurry, I got to see him!
打呀，打呀
Whack, whack, whack!
爸！  什么？雷恩！
Dad!  What? Ryan!
这是我的伎俩  雷恩，不！
I planned this.  Ryan, no!
宇宙秩序终于逆转了
At long last, the cosmic balance has shifted.
跟紧我 猎物变成掠食动物
Stay close.  Prey has become predator!
掠食动物变成猎物
And predator has become prey!
草食动物终于打败肉食动物
And the hoof finally trumps the claw!
爸，来吧 让我们教训这些牛肉干
Come on, Dad! Let's show these turkey-jerkies
让他们知道谁才是老大
who's at the top of the food chain!
先把小狮子吃掉
Let's eat the brat first.
想都别想
Over my dead body!
好耶
Yeah.
爸！
Dad!
我们不想办法 他就会把山大王杀死
He's gonna kill Samson if we don't do something!
咱们何不使用秘密绝招？
Why don't we use the secret play?
我知道 赖瑞，闭嘴，那太蠢了
I know. Shut up, Larry. That's stupid.
不，那太聪明了
No! It's brilliant!
当我提到预兆他们就笑我
They laughed at me when I spoke of the Omen.
看看现在谁还敢笑
But look who's laughing now!
左边一点，好 不对，右边一点
Little to the left. Yeah. No! Little to the right!
下一层 食物链最底端
Next floor: Bottom of the food chain!
叮！
Ding!
发射！
Fire!
我得找更大的武器
We gotta find something bigger!
我知道哪里有更大的武器
I know where we can find something bigger.
预备，雷恩  拉紧一点
Ready, Ryan?  Dig deep!
你应该待在家里
You should have stayed at home.
咱们的祭坛会是你的坟墓
Now our shrine will become your tomb.
发射
Fire!
雷恩！
Ryan!
通常在上主菜之前
I don't typically eat dessert
我不会先吃甜点
before the main course!
离我儿子远一点
Get away from my son!
雷恩
Ryan.
雷恩，你没事吧？
Ryan, are you still with me?
我没事，我只想告诉你
It's OK, Dad. I just want you to know
很遗憾你不像我 有一个好父亲
I'm sorry you didn't have a father like the one I have.
雷恩
Ryan.
好感人哦
How touching.
不过临终遗言通常都很感人
But then, last words usually are.
解决他们
Finish them.
你们在干吗？
What are you doing?
我命令你们攻击他们 就像真正的掠食动物那样
I command you to attack them, like true predators!
我们不是掠食动物 不想再假装下去
We're tired of pretending to be something we're not.
更重要的是，我们受够你了
But most of all, we're tired of you.
布雷，好吧
Blag. Fine.
那我就亲手杀死他们
I'll kill them myself!
爸，记得你在故事里 总是告诉我
Dad, remember what you always told me in your stories:
鼓起勇气
Dig deep.
好耶，宝贝
Oh, yeah, baby!
我们走吧
Let's go.
好
Yeah.
来吧，我们离开这鬼地方  快走吧
Come on, let's get out of here!  Get out of here!
我要在大家面前说 我一直都讨厌你编的舞
And for the record, I've always hated your choreography.
真的很…俗耶
It's so... '80s.
没错，跑吧
That's right! Run!
就像胆小的猎物逃跑吧
Run like the cowardly prey that you are!
我会猎杀你们
I will hunt you down!
大伙儿，快到船上
Everyone! To the boat!
食物链的顶端，妈！
Top of the food chain, Ma!
食物链的顶端…
Top of the food chain...
我是小可爱，我爱你 我是小可爱，我爱你
I'm so cuddly! I like you! I'm so cuddly! I like you!
我是小可爱，我爱你 我是小可爱
I'm so cuddly! I like you! I'm so cuddly!
快点，不然就逃不了
Hurry! We're never gonna make it!
用力推，毛绒绒的怪胎，快推
Push, you crazy, hairy monsters! Push!
赖瑞，打倒档  倒档
Larry, throw it in reverse!  Reverse throwing!
至少我在大草原消失前 目睹这一切
At least I saw the wild before it disappeared.
我还是看得到它，它就在…
I can still see it. It's right...
我的心中 我找到我的吼声
Here. I found my roar.
我们都找到了，儿子
We both did, son.
爸，这是我们第一个 「山大王和雷恩」的故事
You know, Dad, this'll be our first story of Samson and Ryan the Wild.
我想不会有人相信吧
I don't think anybody's gonna believe it.
炸弹来袭
Incoming!
我是小可爱
I'm so cuddly!
Cuddly! I'm so cuddly!
我知道你很可爱 可是你会飘浮吗？
I know you're cuddly. But can you float?
今天真是个 美好的一天
I'm having a  Really nice day
美好的一天 美好的一天
Really nice day Really nice day
向左踢
Step-kick left!
美好的一天
Really nice day
向右踢
Step-kick right!
非常好  不，棒呆了
Splendid.  No! Smashing. Hey!
超厉害的  你们真的觉得很棒吗？
Stupendous!  Are you guys sure about this?
脱胎换骨行动已经完成
Operation Snake-Over is now complete.
大伙儿看，我是秘密情报员
Hey, look, everyone! I'm a secret agent!
BJ，我知道啦 你不只是身材高挑的女神
Bridget, I get it. You're more than a tall, lanky goddess.
也是坚强独立的女性
You're a strong, independent female.
不需要靠交男朋友来证明自己
You don't need to be defined by your relationship
我也尊重你这一点  该是时候了
and I, I respect that.  It's about time.
那是什么？
What was that?
你每天的BJ维他命 宝贝儿
Just your daily dose of vitamin Bridget, baby.
好耶
Oh, yeah yeah!
美好的一天 美好的一天
Really nice day Really nice day
小心！
Look out!
向前踢，向侧踢、向前走
Step-kick, pivot-kick, walk, walk, walk.
好耶，你们看到没？ 你们看！
Yes! Did y'all see that? Check this!
好耶，布雷！好耶，布雷！
Go, Blag! Go, Blag! Go, Blag!
喂，布雷
Hey, Blag.
舞池里不准停车  停车？
No parkin' on the dance floor.  Parkin'?
爸？
Dad?
让开，大家伙
Make some room there, big guy!
美好的一天 非常美好的一天
Really nice day Really, really nice day
好耶
Yeah!
很赞吧，很狂野吧？
Pretty crazy, right? Pretty wild!
老实说
Well, technically, it...
是挺棒的
It's awesome.
好耶
Yes, right.
我本来就要这么说  来吧，大家一起来跳舞
I was just gonna say that.  Come on! Everyone!
回家的旅程会很漫长
This is gonna be a long ride home.
今天真是个
I'm havin' a
美好的一天 非常美好的一天
Really nice day Really nice day, really nice day
今天真是个 我是小可爱，我爱你
I'm having a  I'm so cuddly, I like you
你好
G'day
你干吗要这样？ 你以为很好玩吗？
What are you doing this for? What, do you think it's funny?
给我出去
Just get out.
不好意思哦，各位，歹势啦
Sorry about that, everybody. Sorry.
你好
Hello.
继续吧
Do carry on.
谢谢观赏
来吧！
Come on!
野蛮任务
好了 请大家有秩序地走出戏院
All right, everybody exit in an orderly...
大家排成一排…
All right, single file! Keep it...
我在这部电影里 怎么不是惨叫就是跌倒呢？
I seem to do a lot of falling and screaming in this adventure.